Guide to the Yale Student Reminiscences
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale student reminiscences
1815-2011
RU 809
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.35
(11 boxes)
The materials consist of correspondence, diary excerpts, and autobiographical writings documenting the lives of Yale students. Includes an interview by Cam Carr Polk with Elizabeth Boyd Carr (wife of Louis B. Carr) concerning her husband's discovery of Frisbee.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 41 (YRG 41), Material documenting Yale student life.
Conditions Governing Access
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Arrangement
Arranged by accession.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Accession 2014-A-083 was a gift of Keith W. Wheelock, 2014.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of correspondence, diary excerpts, and autobiographical writings documenting the lives of Yale students. Includes an interview by Cam Carr Polk with Elizabeth Boyd Carr (wife of Louis B. Carr) concerning her husband's discovery of Frisbee.
College students; Reminiscences; Videotapes; Yale College (1718-1887) -- Students; Yale University -- Students
- Notebook of Jennet M. Belknap, 1895 January 18-27; Accession 1987-A-077
  - A notebook of Jennet M. Belknap containing description and memorabilia of a week's trip to Yale to visit Edgar Auchinclass (Y. 1896), 1895 January 18-27 (Box 1)
- Meigs, Josiah (Y. 1778) ALS, 1815 October 13; Accession 1979-A-036
  - Meigs, Josiah (Y. 1778) ALS [1 folder], 1815 October 13 (Box 1)
- Manuscript signed Mason Myltice "Overnight at Yale", Accession 1986-A-068
  - Manuscript signed Mason Myltice "Overnight at Yale." (Box 1)
- Memoir of Charles M. Fleischner, Accession 1986-A-097
  - Memoir of Charles M. Fleischner (Y. 1923), By Memory Alone," 149 pp. (Box 1)
- Thomas N. Cross, "Stories Father Used to Tell", 1983; Accession 1987-A-026
  - "Stories Father Used to Tell" by Thomas N. Cross, M.D. about his father W. Redmond Cross, Yale Class of 1896., 1983 (Box 1)
- Autobiography of Anthony L. Miche, 1990; Accession 1992-A-033
  - Autobiography of Anthony L. Michel, 1990 (Box 1)
- "Yale Students in Oxford and Britain: A Memoir" records, 1948; Accession 2000-A-027; 0.02; (1 envelope) (Box 1)
- Diary excerpts from K. Seeger Carbajal, Accession 2002-A-144
  - Diary excerpts from K. Seeger Carbajal, MED, concerning the Architecture program, 1968-1970 (Box 1)
- Rufus Arthur Wheeler, circa 1926-1975; Accession 2003-A-112
  - Rufus Arthur Wheeler, class of 1926, includes photograph of Yale Banjo Club, ca. and manuscripts by Wheeler, circa 1926-1975 (Box 1)
- Interview of Sam Carr Polk, Yale College Class of 1947, and Elizabeth Boyd Carr about the development of the Frisbie game, 2004; Accession 2005-A-107; 0.25; (1 videotape) (Box 1)
- Letters of W.H. Van Deventer, 1864-1865; Accession 2008-A-021; 0.02; (1 envelope) (Box 1)
- Keith W. Wheelock, 2011; Accession 2014-A-083
  - "A Worm's Eye View of Diplomacy, Finance, and Education: Keith Wheelock's Comments at the 60th Anniversary of PEA [Phillips Exeter Academy] '51, May 6, 2011" (Box 1)
    General
    Includes references to his years as a Yale undergraduate (Class of 1955).